Inventory of the Addition to the Papers of Hardy Cross Dillard 1970-1979
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
Addition to the Papers of Hardy Cross Dillard 1970-1979
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
MSS 84-8d
The addition consists of 12 boxes.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The bulk of this addition to the Hardy Cross Dillard Papers was given to the library by his daughter, Joan Dillard, in March of 1990.
Scope and Content Information
The bulk of this addition consists of his correspondence with personal as well as professional acquaintances for the years 1910-1971. Frequent correspondents include Phillip Jessup, Myres S. McDougal, Charlotte Kohler and Eberhard Deutsch, and occasional correspondents are such prominent figures as Robert Kennedy, Dean Rusk, John Stennis and George Kennan. Other legal scholars with whom Dillard corresponded include Lon Fuller, Arnold Wolfers and John Bassett Moore. These papers also contains several of Dillard's speeches, most of which deal with international relations. Several files pertain to his law practice, including his oral argument in Almond v. Day, a case concerning the payment of state funds to certain eligible children allowing them to attend private schools. Finally, several folders document Dillard's activities in university and alumni organizations.
Contents List
- Alumni 1962-66 (Box 78)
- AALS (Association of American Law Schools) 1963 (Box 78)
- Bricker Amendment 1954 (Box 78)
- Civil Affairs Division 1945 (Box 78)
- Class of 1927 1932 (Box 78)
- Class of 1927 1937 (Box 78)
- Class of 1927 1947 (Box 78)
- Columbia Law School 1962-63, 2 folders (Box 78)
- Estoppel 1934-35 (Box 78)
- Family Correspondence 1910, 1917 (Box 78)
- International Court of Justice 1969-71, 3 folders (Box 78)
- Jurisprudence Fragments 1962, 1965-67 (Box 78)
- Miscellaneous Notes 1956-58, 1963, 1966, n.d. (Box 78)
- Miscellany n.d., 2 folders (Box 79)
- National War College 1938, 1944, 1946-47, 1960 (Box 79)
- Notes: Lectures 1949 (?), 1951 (Box 79)
- Notes: Books, Articles, Speeches 1953, 1955, 1959 (Box 79)
- Notes: Books and Articles (corr. with Rear Admiral Robert Powers, Jr. concerning Cuban missile crisis) 1962, n.d. (Box 79)
- Peace-time Universal Conscription 1945 (Box 79)
- Personal Correspondence 1926-71, 52 folders (Box 79-87)
- Practice: Almond v. Day 1954-55, 15 folders (Box 87)
- Practice: Board of Education of Prince George's County v. Arlington Air Conditioning 1959 (Box 88)
- Practice: Coal Case 1958 (?) (Box 88)
- Practice: Miscellaneous Records and Briefs 1926 (Box 88)
- Practice: Minneapolis-Honeywell v. Arlington Air Conditioning 1958-59 (Box 88)
- Practice: U.S. Industries v. Camco 1956-60, 4 folders (Box 88)
- Seminar Papers 1950, 1957 (Box 88)
- U. Va. Sesquicentennial 1969 (Box 88)
- Virginia Bar Association 1946-7 (Box 88)
- Speech: "Arresting the Soviet Threat" 1952-53 (Box 88)
- Speeches: Miscellaneous Notes 1946-66 (Box 89)
- Speeches: Va. Federation of Women's Clubs; Chamber of Commerce/William Battle Dinner 1964, 1966 (Box 89)
- Speeches: The National War College, The Hague 1958, n.d. (Box 89)
- Speeches: Anglo-American Relations 1954 (Box 89)
- Speeches: Recognitions of China 1963, 1965-68 (Box 89)
- Speeches: "Restraints on Foreign Policy" 1952 (Box 89)
- Speeches: Richmond Bar Assoc. -- "National Security and the Future" 1947 (Box 89)